A Guide to the Correspondence of the Speaker of the House of Delegates, 1960-1980.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
House of Delegates, Speaker of the - Correspondence
1960-1980.
The Library of Virginia
30670
Virginia. General Assembly. House of Delegates. Speaker.
13.3 cubic feet (38 boxes)
Biographical/Historical Information
The House of Delegates' predecessor, the House of Burgesses, was modeled after the House of Commons, in Parliament. The House of Burgesses existed from 1643 to 1776. The first session of the General Assembly, which took place in 1776, established the first constitution and made the House of Delegates the most powerful branch in state government. It was not until the constitution of 1851 was adopted that a more equitable balance among the branches of government was established. In the General Assembly, members of the House of Delegates and the Senate vote on legislation entered during the legislative session. Legislative bills can originate either in the House of Delegates or in the Senate, with both chambers having the ability to establish study committees. Each serves as a check upon the other to ensure a thorough debate on the merits of each bill. Currently the House of Delegates, together with the Senate, meets as the General Assembly in annual session, alternatively during thirty to sixty days.
John Warren Cooke served in the House of Delegates from 1942-1980 and was Speaker of the House from 1968-1980 when he retired. He represented Essex, Gloucester, King and Queen, King William, Mathews and Middlesex Counties.
Scope and Content
These are letters received and sent, and subject files of the Office of the Speaker John Warren Cooke, 1960-1980. Correspondents include constituents, lobbyists, legislators, and other public officials, and the subjects range from the Equal Rights Amendment through septic tank permits to the remodeling of the Life of Virginia Insurance building for General Assembly offices. Also includes information on appointments of House members to commissions and committees. The papers are arranged alphabetically by folder subject headings.
Also includes seven sets of architectural plans and drawing concerning the remodeling of the Life of Virginia Insurance Company building for use as a General Assembly office building and one set of plans concerning the renovation of the Richmond West Hotel for use as state offices.
There is also microfilm of correspondence, invititations, and speeches of Speaker of the House of Delegates John Warren Cooke, covering 1972-1979. The microfilm is filed with the collection.
Arranged chronologically by report date. Records have been kept in their original order.
Acquisition Information
Accession 30670 was transferred John Warren Cooke, March 20, 1980.
Contents List
- Correspondence of the Speaker of the House of Delegates, 1960-1980 (Accession 30670)., Extent: 13.3 cubic feet (38 boxes)
  - Administrative Assistant to the Speaker, 1973. (Box 1)
  - Administrative Assistant to the Speaker, 1977. (Box 1)
  - Appropriations Committee, 1976. (Box 1)
  - Audit of the General Assembly, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Automated Data Processing, 1972. (Box 1)
  - Bermuda, 1970. (Box 1)
  - Bicentennial Commission, 1977. (Box 1)
  - Bills, 1975-1979. (Box 1)
  - Bills - Enrolled, 1978. (Box 1)
  - Bills - Enrolled, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Bills - Prefiled, 1970. (Box 1)
  - Bills - Requests, 1978. (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1979. (Box 1)
  - Budget - Education requests, 1973, 1975, 1977. (Box 1)
  - Byrd, Harry - Memoral Commission, 1974-1976. (Box 1)
  - Capitol Expansion, 1973. (Box 1)
  - Census, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Chesapeake Bay - Information, 1974. (Box 1)
  - Civil Defense, 1967-1972. (Box 2)
  - Commissions, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Commissions - Appointments, 1970. (Box 2)
  - Commissions - Appointments, 1971. (Box 2)
  - Commissions - Appointments, 1972. (Box 2)
  - Commissions - Appointments, 1973. (Box 2)
  - Commissions - Appointments, 1973-1975. (Box 3)
  - Commissions - Appointments, 1974-1975. (Box 3)
  - Commissions - Appointments, 1976-1977. (Box 3)
  - Commissions - Appointments, 1977. (Box 3)
  - Commissions - Appointments, 1978. (Box 3)
  - Commissions - Appointments, 1979. (Box 3)
  - Commissions - House Membership of, 19. (Box 4)
  - Commissions - Requests, 1973-1975. (Box 4)
  - Commissions - Requests, 1974. (Box 4)
  - Commissions - Requests, 1978. (Box 4)
  - Committees, undated. (Box 4)
  - Committees - Assignments, 1967-1972. (Box 4)
  - Committees - Assignments, 1973-1974. (Box 4)
  - Committees - Assignments, 1974-1975. (Box 5)
  - Committees - Assignments, 1976. (Box 5)
  - Committees - Assignments, 1976-1977. (Box 5)
  - Committees - Assignments, 1977-1978. (Box 5)
  - Committees - House Standing, 1972, 1774-1975. (Box 5)
  - Committees - Requests, 1973-1975. (Box 5)
  - Committees - Requests, 1975-1977. (Box 5)
  - Committees - Requests, 1976-1978. (Box 5)
  - Committees - Requests and assignments, 1972. (Box 6)
  - Community Colleges, 1972. (Box 6)
  - Conflict of Interest statements, 1970-1975. (Box 6)
  - Constituents, 1973-1974. (Box 6)
  - Constituents, 1975. (Box 6)
  - Constituents - Consumer Affairs, 1973. (Box 6)
  - Constituents - Corrections, 1978. (Box 6)
  - Constituents - Education, 1972-1976. (Box 6)
  - Constituents - Miscellaneous, 1974-1977. (Box 6)
  - Constituents - Problems, 1977-1979. (Box 6)
  - Constituents - Septic Tanks, 1972-1977. (Box 6)
  - Constituents - Welfare and Medicaid, 1973-1976. (Box 6)
  - Constitutional Amendment Referendum, 1970. (Box 7)
  - Cooke, John Warren - Account as Executor of Estate of Bessie Miller Hoskins Smith, 1973. (Box 7)
  - Cooke, John Warren - Biographical sketches, 1976. (Box 7)
  - Cooke, John Warren - Biographical sketches, 1976-1979. (Box 7)
  - Cooke, John Warren - Correspondence, 1974. (Box 7)
  - Cooke, John Warren - Correspondence, 1975. (Box 7)
  - Corrections, Dept. of, 1976-1978. (Box 7)
  - Correspondence (A-F), 1973-1974. (Box 7)
  - Correspondence - Democratic Party, 1973-1974. (Box 7)
  - Correspondence (G), 1973-1974. (Box 8)
  - Correspondence - Health, Dept. of, 1973-1974. (Box 8)
  - Correspondence - Highways, Dept. of, 1973-1974. (Box 8)
  - Correspondence (J-N), 1973-1974. (Box 8)
  - Correspondence (L-P, W), 1973-1974. (Box 8)
  - Correspondence (O-Z), 1973-1974. (Box 9)
  - Correspondence (A-B), 1975. (Box 9)
  - Correspondence (C-D), 1975. (Box 9)
  - Correspondence (E-F), 1975. (Box 9)
  - Correspondence (G), 1975. (Box 9)
  - Correspondence (H), 1975. (Box 9)
  - Correspondence (I-M), 1975. (Box 10)
  - Correspondence (N-Q), 1975. (Box 10)
  - Correspondence (R-S), 1975. (Box 10)
  - Correspondence (T-U), 1975. (Box 10)
  - Correspondence (V-Z), 1975. (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1976 Apr-Sept. (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1976 Oct-Dec. (Box 10)
  - Correspondence (A-B), 1976. (Box 11)
  - Correspondence (C-D), 1976. (Box 11)
  - Correspondence (E-F), 1976. (Box 11)
  - Correspondence (G-H), 1976. (Box 11)
  - Correspondence (I-L), 1976. (Box 11)
  - Correspondence (M-O), 1976. (Box 11)
  - Correspondence (P-R), 1976. (Box 11)
  - Correspondence (S), 1976. (Box 12)
  - Correspondence (T-Z), 1976. (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1977 Jan. (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1977 Feb. (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1977 Mar. (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1977 Apr-Aug. (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1977 Sept-Dec. (Box 13)
  - Correspondence - Corporation, 1977. (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1978 Jan. (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1978 Feb. (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1978 Mar. (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1978 Apr-Dec. (Box 13)
  - Correspondence (A), 1978-1979. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence (B), 1978-1979. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence - Board of Supervisors, 1978-1979. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence (C), 1978-1979. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence (D), 1978-1979. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence - Dept. of Health, Shellfish, etc., 1978-1979. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence - Dept. of Highways, 1978-1979. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence (E), 1978-1979. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence (F), 1978-1979. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence (G), 1978-1979. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence - General Assembly of Virginia, Index, 1978-1979. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence (H), 1978-1979. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence - House of Delegates, Clerk, 1978-1979. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence (I-J), 1978-1979. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence - Jamestown, 1978-1979. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence (K), 1978-1979. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence (L), 1978-1979. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence (M), 1978-1979. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence - Middle Peninsual Planning District Commission, 1978-1979. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence (N), 1978-1979. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence - National Conference of State Legislatures, 1978-1979. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence (O), 1978-1979. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence (P), 1978-1979. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence - Pages, 1978-1979. (Box 15)
  - Correspondence (Q), 1978-1979. (Box 16)
  - Correspondence (R), 1978-1979. (Box 16)
  - Correspondence - Rules Committee, 1978-1979. (Box 16)
  - Correspondence (S), 1978-1979. (Box 16)
  - Correspondence (T), 1978-1979. (Box 16)
  - Correspondence (U), 1978-1979. (Box 16)
  - Correspondence (V), 1978-1979. (Box 16)
  - Correspondence (W), 1978-1979. (Box 16)
  - Correspondence (X, Y, Z), 1978-1979. (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, 1979 Jan. (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, 1979 Feb. (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, 1979 Mar. (Box 17)
  - Council on State Governments - Committee on Suggested State Legislation, 1975. (Box 17)
  - Counties - Boards of Supervisors, 1973-1974. (Box 17)
  - County Governments, 1977-1978. (Box 17)
  - Democratic Caucus, 1973-1974. (Box 17)
  - Democratic Caucus, 1978. (Box 17)
  - Dress Code, 1976. (Box 17)
  - Elections, 1975. (Box 17)
  - Employment requests, 1978-1979. (Box 17)
  - Engineering and Buildings, Division of, 1978-1979. (Box 17)
  - Equal Rights Amendemnts, 1972-1974. (Box 17)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, 1978. (Box 17)
  - Equal Rigts Amendment, 1979. (Box 17)
  - Equal Rights Amendment - Equality Yes! E.R.A. No!, 1978. (Box 17)
  - Equal Rights Amendment - Extension Resolution, 1978. (Box 17)
  - Expenses, Delegate, 1976-1977. (Box 18)
  - Expenses, Delegate, 1978. (Box 18)
  - Exepenses, Delegate - Summary of, 1978. (Box 18)
  - First Continental Congress, Philadelphia, PA, 1974. (Box 18)
  - Forms, 1977. (Box 18)
  - General Assembly - Correspondence, 1971. (Box 18)
  - General Assembly - Correspondence, 1972 Jan. (Box 18)
  - General Assembly - Correspondence, 1972 Feb. (Box 18)
  - General Assembly - Correspondence, 19. (Box 19)
  - General Assembly - Correspondence - General, 1972. (Box 19)
  - General Assembly - Correspondence - Proposed legislation, 1972. (Box 19)
  - General Assembly - Correspondence (A-G), 1973. (Box 19)
  - General Assembly - Correspondence - General, 1973. (Box 19)
  - General Assembly - Correspondence, 1974. (Box 19)
  - General Assembly - Correspondence, 1974-1975. (Box 19)
  - General Assembly - Correspondence, 1975. (Box 19)
  - General Assembly - Correspondence - Budget request, 1975-1976. (Box 19)
  - General Assembly - Correspondence - Clerical, 1973-1977. (Box 20)
  - General Assembly - Correspondence - Legislative Summary, 1974-1976. (Box 20)
  - General Assembly Building, 1976. (Box 20)
  - General Assembly Building, 1977-1978. (Box 20)
  - General Assembly Building - Budget, 1977-1978. (Box 20)
  - General Assembly Building - Food Service contract, 1977. (Box 20)
  - General Assembly Building - Furnishings, 1977-1978. (Box 20)
  - General Assembly Building Furnishings - Complaints, 1978. (Box 20)
  - General Assembly Building - Furniture inventory, undated. (Box 20)
  - General Assembly Building - Improvements, 1978-1979. (Box 20)
  - General Assembly Building - Joint Rules Committee, 1975-1976. (Box 20)
  - General Assembly Building - Joint Rules Committee, 1977. (Box 21)
  - General Assembly Building - Miscellaneous, 1977-1978. (Box 21)
  - General Assembly Building - Rules Committee - Change Orders, 1977-1978. (Box 21)
  - General Assembly Building - Security, 1978-1979. (Box 21)
  - General Assembly Building - Staff Interior Design, 1976-1977. (Box 21)
  - "The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Virginia, 1962-1974, [Chapters 1-3], 1976. (Box 21)
  - "The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Virginia, 1962-1974, [Chapters 4-8], 1976. (Box 21)
  - "The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Virginia, 1962-1974, [Chapters 9-11], 1976. (Box 22)
  - "The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Virginia, 1962-1974, [Chapters 12-18], 1976. (Box 22)
  - "General Fund Revenue Estimates for Fiscal Years 1980, 1981, and 1982", 1979. (Box 22)
  - Governor's Advisory Board on the Budget, 1969-1970, 1973. (Box 22)
  - Governor's Management Study Implementation Commission, 1971-1972. (Box 22)
  - Grants - Federal, 1976. (Box 22)
  - Grants - National Science Foundation, 1977-1978. (Box 22)
  - Hampton Roads Tour, 1978. (Box 23)
  - Health, Dept. of, 1977-1978. (Box 23)
  - Highways - General, 1966-1973. (Box 23)
  - Highways - Individual requests, 1976-1971. (Box 23)
  - Highways and Transportation, Dept. of, 1974-1976. (Box 23)
  - Historical Events, 1975-1976. (Box 23)
  - History, 1979. (Box 23)
  - Hospital - Gloucester County, 1973. (Box 23)
  - House of Delegates - Calendar, Bills and Resolutions Referred, 1979 Jan 10-Feb 2. (Box 23)
  - House of Delegates - Calendar, Bills and Resolutions Referred, 1979 Feb 5-24. (Box 23)
  - House of Delegates - Clerks, 1974. (Box 24)
  - House of Delegates - General, 1970. (Box 24)
  - House of Delegates - Legislation, 1969-1970. (Box 24)
  - Inauguration, 1974, 1978. (Box 24)
  - Income Tax Study Commission, 1966. (Box 24)
  - Interns, Virginia Legislative, 1973-1975. (Box 24)
  - Interstate Highway Study Commission, 1974. (Box 24)
  - Invitations, 1971-1972. (Box 24)
  - Invitations, 1973. (Box 24)
  - Invitations, 1976. (Box 25)
  - Invitations, 1977. (Box 25)
  - Invitations, 1978. (Box 25)
  - Invitations, 1979. (Box 25)
  - Jamestown - Corporation, 1970-1971. (Box 25)
  - Jamestown - Foundation, 1967-1972. (Box 25)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission, 1978-1979. (Box 25)
  - Judges, 1975-1979. (Box 25)
  - Legis 50, 1973-1976. (Box 25)
  - Legis 50, 1976-1979. (Box 25)
  - Legislation, 1973. (Box 26)
  - Legislation, 1975 Dec-1976 Jan. (Box 26)
  - Legislation, 1976 Feb. (Box 26)
  - Legislation, 1976 Mar. (Box 26)
  - Legislation, 1977. (Box 26)
  - Legislative - Analyst, Guide for, 1971. (Box 27)
  - Legislative - Budget, 1976-1978. (Box 27)
  - Legislative - Budget, 1978-1980. (Box 27)
  - Legislative - Compensation Questionaires, 1973. (Box 27)
  - Legislative - Department Expenditures, 1968-1976. (Box 27)
  - Legislative - Efficiency, 1973, 1975-1976. (Box 27)
  - Legislative - Intern Program, 1977-1980. (Box 27)
  - Legislative - Proceedings, undated. (Box 27)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on, 1968. (Box 27)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on, 1969. (Box 27)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on, 1970-1971. (Box 28)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on, 1971-1972. (Box 28)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on, 1972. (Box 28)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on, 1972-1973. (Box 28)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on, 1973-1974. (Box 28)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on, 1974-1975. (Box 29)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Auditing, 1973. (Box 29)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Consultant Fees, 1973-1974. (Box 29)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Reports, 1975-1976. (Box 29)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Report of the Commission on Legislative Process to the General Assembly of Virginia, 1973. (Box 29)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Report of the Commission on Legislative Process to the General Assembly of Virginia, 1974. (Box 29)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Report to the Commission on the Legislative Process, 1973. (Box 29)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Subcommittees - Computers, 1972-1973. (Box 29)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Subcommittees - Computers, 1973. (Box 30)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Subcommittees - Computers, 1974-1975. (Box 30)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Subcommittees - Facilities, 1971-1973. (Box 30)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Subcommittees - Facilities, 1974-1975. (Box 30)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Subcommittees - Joint Legislative Audit and Review, 1974. (Box 30)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Subcommittees - Miscellaneous matters, 1978. (Box 30)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Subcommittees - Procedures, 1972. (Box 30)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Subcommittees - Procedures, 1974-1975. (Box 30)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Subcommittees - Records and Documents, 1969-1970, 1972. (Box 30)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Subcommittees - Staffing, 1972. (Box 30)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Subcommittees - Staffing, 1974-1975. (Box 30)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Subcommittees - Services, Division of, 1978-1979. (Box 30)
  - Legislative - Process, Commission on - Subcommittees - Summaries, 1979. (Box 30)
  - Library, 1978. (Box 30)
  - Lobbyists - Lists of, 1977-1979. (Box 30)
  - Lobbyists, Study Commission on, 1974-1975. (Box 30)
  - Lobbyists, Study Commission on, 1975-1976. (Box 31)
  - Mace, Day of Fasting, etc. - Notes, 1974. (Box 31)
  - Maison Caree, 1972. (Box 31)
  - Maps, 1977-1978. (Box 31)
  - Marinas Study, 1973-1974. (Box 31)
  - Marine Resources Commission, 1978-1979. (Box 31)
  - Mathews County - Origin of name, undated. (Box 31)
  - McMurran, Lewis A., Jr., 1978. (Box 31)
  - Members of the House, 1978. (Box 31)
  - Menhaden Information, 1975. (Box 31)
  - Mental Health and Mental Retardation, 1973-1976. (Box 31)
  - Mental Health and Mentatl Retardation, Dept. of, 1976. (Box 31)
  - Mental Retardation Planning Council, 1967-1968. (Box 31)
  - Messenger Service, 1974. (Box 31)
  - Mini Journal, 1976. (Box 31)
  - Mini Journal, 1977. (Box 31)
  - Mitchell, H. Bryan - Correspondence, 1973. (Box 31)
  - Mitchell, H. Bryan - Correspondence, 1974 Jan-Feb. (Box 31)
  - Mitchell, H. Bryan - Correspondence, 1974 Mar-Apr. (Box 31)
  - Mitchell, H. Bryan - Correspondence, 1974 May-July. (Box 31)
  - Mitchell, H. Bryan - Correspondence, 1974 Aug-Dec. (Box 32)
  - Mitchell, H. Bryan - Correspondence, 1975 Jan. (Box 32)
  - Mitchell, H. Bryan - Correspondence, 1975 Feb. (Box 32)
  - Mitchell, H. Bryan - Correspondence, 1975 Mar. (Box 32)
  - Moore, E. Blackburn, Speaker, 1960. (Box 32)
  - National Conference of State Legislative Leaders, 1969-1971. (Box 32)
  - National Conference of State Legislative Leaders, 1972-1974. (Box 32)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures, 1976-1977. (Box 32)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures, 1978-1979. (Box 32)
  - Newsletter - UVA, 1975. (Box 33)
  - News Releases, 1977-1979. (Box 33)
  - Organization Chart - State Government, 1974. (Box 33)
  - Orientation, New Member, 1972-1973, 1977. (Box 33)
  - Orientation, New Member, 1979. (Box 33)
  - Pages - Applications, 1970. (Box 33)
  - Pages - Applications, 1971. (Box 33)
  - Pages - General, 1974. (Box 33)
  - Pages - General, 1975-1977. (Box 33)
  - Pages - Special Session, 1968. (Box 33)
  - Photographs, 1979. (Box 33)
  - Physicians - Malpractice Insurance, 1975. (Box 33)
  - Position Papers, 1979. (Box 33)
  - Post Offices, 1966-1969, 1972. (Box 33)
  - Potomac River Study Commission, 1968. (Box 33)
  - Press Releases, 1978-1979. (Box 33)
  - Public Defender Commission, 1973. (Box 33)
  - Purchases and Supply, Dept. of, 1973. (Box 33)
  - Questionnaires and Survey Requests, 1975. (Box 33)
  - Rape and Sexual Assault Statutes, 1976. (Box 33)
  - Recommendations, 1976-1979. (Box 34)
  - Redistricting, 1971. (Box 34)
  - Reports - Comprehensive Long Range Master Plan for Juvenile and Youthful Offender Justice Systems in the Commonwealth of Virginia, 1974. (Box 34)
  - Reports - Council of Higher Education, 1979. (Box 34)
  - Reports - Evaluation for the Commonwealth of Virginia: Salaries and Fringe Benefits Classification Plan Maintenance, 1972. (Box 34)
  - Reports - Financial Status of State Departments and Commission, 1972. (Box 34)
  - Reports - Middle Peninsula Health District, 1978. (Box 34)
  - Reports - National Guard, 1979. (Box 34)
  - Reports - State Jobs and Salaris, 1972 c.. (Box 34)
  - Reports - Task Force on Criminal Justice Goals and Objectives, 1978. (Box 35)
  - Reports - Tax Limitations, 1979. (Box 35)
  - Report To Richmond Circuit Court, Part I, of Grand Jury Investigation Problems within the Virginia Dept. of Corrections, 1974. (Box 35)
  - Reports - Virginia Commission on Interstate Cooperation, 1978. (Box 35)
  - Reports - Virginia Liaison Office, 1978. (Box 35)
  - Republican Party Caucus, 1978. (Box 35)
  - Requests for information, 1976-1977. (Box 35)
  - Resignations, 1978-1979. (Box 35)
  - Resolutions, 1973, 1975. (Box 35)
  - Resolutions - Creating a commission to study the feasibility of statewide public television coverage of the activities of the legislature, 1974. (Box 35)
  - Resolutions - Procedural, 1971. (Box 35)
  - Resolutions- Received from other states, 1976-1979. (Box 35)
  - Retirement - Announcement, 1979. (Box 35)
  - Retirment - Petition against, 1977. (Box 35)
  - Revenue Sharing, 1972. (Box 35)
  - Richmond, City of - Raw sewage, 1969. (Box 35)
  - Rules - Committee, 1972-1973. (Box 35)
  - Rules - Committee, 1973-1974. (Box 35)
  - Rules - Committee, 1974-1975. (Box 35)
  - Rules - Committee, 1975. (Box 35)
  - Rules - Committee, 1976-1979. (Box 36)
  - Rules - Committee, 1977. (Box 36)
  - Rules - Committee, 1978-1979. (Box 36)
  - Rules - Committee - Docket, 1978. (Box 36)
  - Rules - Committee - Docket, 1979. (Box 36)
  - Rules - Committee - Reports to, 1978. (Box 36)
  - Rules - Forms, 1973. (Box 36)
  - Rules - House, 1978. (Box 36)
  - Rules - House, 1979. (Box 36)
  - Rules - House - Study Commission, 1969-1970. (Box 36)
  - Rules - Senate, 1971, 1975. (Box 36)
  - Seating arrangements, 1975-1976, 1978-1979. (Box 36)
  - Septic tank permits, 1972-1973. (Box 36)
  - Signage, 1978-1979. (Box 36)
  - Social Security help, 1973-1975. (Box 36)
  - Southern States Speaker's Conference, 1976. (Box 37)
  - Speaker's Chair, Old House Chamber, 1978. (Box 37)
  - "Speakers and Clerks of the Virginia House of Delegates", 1976-1978. (Box 37)
  - Speeches, 1969, 1973-1975. (Box 37)
  - State Aid to Localities Study Commission, 1978-1979. (Box 37)
  - State Governmental Management, Commission on, 1977. (Box 37)
  - State Police, Dept. of, 1979. (Box 37)
  - State Water Control Board, 1975-1976. (Box 37)
  - Statutory Research, Appointment of the Director of, 1970. (Box 37)
  - Tappahannock Historic District, 1973. (Box 37)
  - Telephone, 1979. (Box 37)
  - U.S.S. Virginia, Silver Service, 1976. (Box 37)
  - U.S.S. Virginia, Silver Service, 1976-1977. (Box 37)
  - Veteran's Affairs, Commission on, 1974. (Box 37)
  - Virginia Advisory Legislative Council, Committee to Study Professions and Occupations - Minutes of meetings, 1972-1973. (Box 37)
  - Virginia Association of Counties, undated. (Box 37)
  - Virginia Code Commission, 1970. (Box 37)
  - Virginia Congress of Parents and Teachers, 1967-1968. (Box 37)
  - Virginia Council of State Legislation, 1967. (Box 37)
  - Virginia Housing Study Commission, 1970. (Box 37)
  - Virginia Institute of Marine Science, 1976, 1978. (Box 37)
  - Virginia is for Lovers, 1979. (Box 38)
  - Virginia Metropolitan Areas Study Commission, 1968. (Box 38)
  - Virginia State Crime Commission, 1973-1974. (Box 38)
  - Virginia State Crime Commission, 1974-1976. (Box 38)
  - Virginia Supplemental Retirement - Act, Blue Cross, Blue Shield, 1972. (Box 38)